

25 Emir Abdelkader Avenue, Akid Lotfi, Bir Eldjir 31000, Oran, Algeria

🛮 (+213) 551-081-911 | 🔀 salim@zidweb.com | 🏕 salimdj.me | 🖸 CaddyDz | 🤟 CaddyDz | 🚵 salim-djerbouh | 🛅 CaddyDz | 💆 @saly3301

Summary

Current Chief Technology Officer and Lead Developer at start-up company Zidweb. 5+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and data structures and pattern architecture. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Skills

DevOps Linux, Digital Ocean, Vagrant, Travis CI, GitHub Actions, CloudFlare, Stripe, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage

Back-end Laravel, NodeJS, ASP.NET Core, MySQL, Redis, REST API, Swagger

Front-end VueJS, VueX, Nuxt, WebPack, Babel, HTML5, CSS3, Vuetify Material, TWBS, ¡Query **Programming** C#, PHP, Python, Perl, Java, Ruby, Objective-C, Swift, C/C++, BASH, ASM x86_64 AT&T, D

Languages English, French, Arabic

Work Experience _____

Zidweb, LLC. Oran, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER, CTO AND LEAD DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020 - Present

- · Provisioned an easily manageable hybrid infrastructure(Digital Ocean Droplets + On-premise) utilizing IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Sentry and OpenVPN
- Manage all DevOps and third party services integration (CloudFlare, Forge, Algolia, Pusher, Vonage)
- · Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Travis CI and GitHub Actions for containerized applications using Docker and Vagrant.
- Implemented, documented RESTful API server for directory listing application (Easy Help in Google Play).
- Wrote and deployed several small scale apps like shopping carts.
- Restructured a +40 million records database of automotive spare parts catalog and implemented a web interface for it
- Created a medical platform to manage requests for operations abroad as well as handle transportation and hotel booking
- Created Backend in Laravel + Frontend in NuxtJS for an ELO Boosting gaming service.

Didata LLC. Remote | Zürich, Switzerland

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

March. 2020 - April. 2020

- Wrote example testing data seeders for BioLab research application
- Implemented an ACL architecture for Backend API
- Wrote mutations mapping module for state management following the Flux pattern for the Frontend application
- Implemented several CRUD models

Upwork. Remote | Germany

FREELANCE BACKEND DEVELOPER

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Feb. 2020

- Wrote and integrated a library for ActiveCampaign mailing lists and contact
- Upgraded framework and libraries versions and refactored code accordingly

EURL PAKIKI Remote | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

ACCOUNTING AND RESEARCH OPERATIONS

Nov. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Implemented several data collection and visualization graphs for sales and expenses of the corporation
- · Created an instant search iPad application implementing Algolia as well as Apple ARKit 4 for vendors in showrooms
- · Installed an configured an RTMP server for live camera feed

A-Tech Solutions LLC. Algiers, Algeria

Jan. 2019 - March. 2019

Feb. 2018 - Sep. 2019

- Wrote an HRM Module in ASP.NET Core for an ERP Platform
- · Ported an existing application to Linux environment
- Wrote a CRUD view module in AngularJS

SARL TPHST. Algiers, Algeria

INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS CONSULTING AND IT SUPPORT

- Managed foreign partners (BSolar, AcoClara, Aquamarine and Leica) meetings, calls and emails
- Done market research for importing machinery from the EU
- · Created an API client in C for fingerprint based office employees check-in device
- Configured cloud based backing and syncing services for documents across the administration
- Automated documents scanning by integrating a third party OCR service in Windows

DIERBOUH SALIM · RESUME FEBRUARY 4, 2021

BitshopitAlgiers, Algeria

CO-FOUNDER AND LEAD DEVELOPER

- · FIFA 2018 video streaming site, implemented RTMP, Redis queues, ffmpeg encoding, VideoJS HLS and Google IMA VAST
- · Database architecture, business logic and API integration of Binance cryptocurrency exchange platform
- · Created a webfront site for a medical clinic and managed its SEO to top Google hits and Alexa rank

AlgoTech Orestor LLC.

Algiers, Algeria

LEAD DEVELOPER AND SYSTEM ADMIN

Mar. 2017 - Dec. 2017

Apr. 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Created an automated online store shopping cart with themes and ordering system
- · Implemented the deployment infrastructure on Linux Debian via bind9 and automated nginx configuration

MNI Martship Remote | Quebec, Canada

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Jun. 2017, Aug. 2017

Boumerdas, Algeria

- Wrote the RTL version of the shopping section on company's site
 Implemented responsive and re-sizable media for faster page loads
- Galaxy EDU

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER Aug. 2016, Mar. 2017

- · Created a web based private school management system with online level testing system and evaluation
- · Wrote Microsoft Office Excel add-ons in VBA to integrated an HRM module

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2016-2021 Top %5, Overall Stack Overflow members

Internationa

Amsterdam, Netherlands

2018-2021 **Top #37**, PHP ranking GitHub awards

DOMESTIC

2021 **1st Place**, Most Active GitHub contributor

Algeria

Presentation

GDG Conference Blida, Algeria

PRESENTER FOR < MACHINE LEARNING THEORY>

Nov. 2017

- Introduced the theory of machine learning genetic algorithms with an analogy of evolutionary biology
- Introduced how machine learning algorithms work with an implementation of an SAT resolver in symbolic regression

CSC Club VCS event

Blida, Algeria

SPEAKER < PRODUCTIVE GIT AND GITHUB WORKFLOWS>

May. 2017

A step by step guide & live demo of GitHub teams workflow, from forks to clones to issues and pull requests to merges and releases.

OpenMinds Linux install party

Algiers, Algeria

A LOOK INTO THE KERNEL INTERNALS>

Apr. 2017

· A brief talk about the Linux kernel source tree and subsystems with a short introduction to OSDev

Education

Harvard University Remote

HARVARD CS50 Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2018

• Passed final tests creating a web server and reverse proxy in C.

USTHB University Algiers, Algeria

FIRST YEAR MATHS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2016 - Oct. 2017

· Dropped out due to outdated material and language barrier (French), switched to self education

Lounici Ali University

Blida, Alaeria

FINAL YEAR ENGLISH LITERATURE

• Dropped out due to lack of interest, switched to computer science

Sep. 2013 - Jan. 2016

FEBRUARY 4, 2021 DJERBOUH SALIM · RESUME 2